PERFECT CROWN
SPONSORED BY: MINISTRY OF
CULTURE, SPORTS AND TOURISM
AND KOREA CREATIVE
CONTENT AGENCY
MBC DRAMA SCRIPT
CONTEST WINNER
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION
CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS
WERE FILMED SAFELY
EPISODE 11
Your Royal Highness,
it is the Queen Mother.
I'd like a brief audience
in the Council Hall.
Do we have time
before we're due at the Throne Hall?
Well…
Yes, we have about 30 minutes.
Right.
Your Royal Highness.
It seems like His Majesty wants to enter
the Throne Hall with you?
His Majesty does?
Yes. It appears he's a bit nervous.
I'll meet you there.
I won't be long.
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Grand Princess.
You must flee.
Isn't that… the Council Hall?
Grand Princess.
No…
No!
Your Highness!
What was that?
Go and see what happened.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Aide Do.
What…
What are you doing here?
Tell me.
Do Hyejeong!
The Council Hall…
His Royal Highness.
He's in the Council Hall.
Your Royal Highness.
No!
- Grand Princess!
- Ms. Seong!
You can't, Grand Princess!
PERFECT CROWN
Is anyone…
Is anyone out there?
Your Royal Highness!
If something terrible happens to you…
You can't…
Let's see this through.
I will be by your side.
Don't come.
Your Royal Highness!
Your Royal Highness…
Your Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness!
Your Royal Highness, you need to wake up.
Your Royal Highness.
I'll get you out of here.
Your Royal Highness, please wake up.
Someone, please save him.
Is anyone out there?
Is there anyone out there?
Please help us…
Your Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness…
Mother!
Your Majesty.
Mother, there's a fire in the palace.
What is he talking about?
A fire has broken out at the Council Hall.
Uncle is…
Is I-AN safe?
Your Majesty…
Answer me!
Is I-AN safe?
You should get some rest, Grand Princess.
The royal physicians said he is stable.
How could you have just run
into the fire like that?
Had Aide Choi not reached you in time,
you would also be…
He would've come to save me.
Pardon?
If it had been me in there, he would have…
come for me too.
To save me.
Like he always has.
Sir, you need to be announced first! Ah…
The Grand Prince is stable, so tomorrow...
How could you just run in there like that?
Lower your voice.
The palace attendants are outside.
Why aren't you at a hospital?
You should at least get proper treatment.
How can I trust any hospital right now?
- What?
- You think this fire was just an accident?
They targeted the Grand Prince
at the wedding, not me.
And now, a fire just breaks out
on abdication day?
You expect me to buy that?
And if it wasn't an accident?
- What?
- What can you do if it wasn't?
Will you collapse and die in his place?
Then what should I have done?
- Just leave him there to die?
- Yes, just leave him!
Jeongwoo.
How much longer
must I watch you be in danger?
How much longer must I endure this?
I've been looking everywhere for you.
What are you doing here?
Are you okay?
Yes.
I'm told the Grand Prince
and Princess are both fine.
You don't need to worry too much.
I'm sorry.
What? Why are you apologizing?
I mean…
I should've never left
the Grand Prince's side, right?
Wait, come on now.
It's not like your being there
would've magically stopped
the fire from starting.
Come on, that's silly.
Wait, hold on. Do you really believe that?
Thank you.
What?
- Grand Princess!
- Ms. Seong!
You can't, Grand Princess!
I'll be right back.
What? Where are you going?
No, you can't!
Aide Choi! Choi Hyeon!
A royal physician!
Summon a royal physician!
Thank goodness…
Thank goodness.
If it weren't for you, they would both be…
Oh.
Stop that.
I mean, I was just doing my job.
I was worried…
that you'd get hurt.
Thank you.
But you know,
I just got all better.
Oh, ow, ow… Hold on. Ow…
Are you okay?
It's so itchy right here.
Can you scratch it for me?
Why are you crying?
Don't cry.
Crying one second and laughing the next?
Just pick one already.
You're no crybaby.
Where are all these tears coming from?
What's wrong? Are you feeling unwell?
Should we go to the hospital?
Why was he…
at the Council Hall today?
He was due to accept
the abdication in the Throne Hall.
Oh…
Prime Minister Min texted,
asking for a quick chat
at the Council Hall.
Jeongwoo…
had him go there?
Yes.
Your Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness!
Stay still.
I must appear…
insanely infatuated with you
for people to believe
this absurd marriage is genuine.
Do not bend to their will.
Do not back away
and do not compromise.
I shall fight with all that I have.
Just as you do.
I have a great deal that you do not…
and if you ask for it,
I fully intend to provide it.
I thought you said
the palace was the safest.
Is there any place safe for you?
The Council Hall was
practically empty at the time.
For an explosion that big,
casualties are minimal.
We will make a joint statement
with the Royal Secretariat...
No need.
Just leave it for now.
Pardon?
Let's leave it until the Grand Prince…
wakes up.
Last night, a major fire broke out
at Gyeongbokgung Palace.
Witnesses at Gwanghwamun Square
reported hearing a loud explosion.
With no official statement
from the palace yet,
there are growing concerns
over the safety of the royal family.
I want the past month's CCTV footage
of the Council Hall interior,
entrance, and corridors.
Have it copied and sent over.
Is three days enough to review?
With Court Lady Choi, Aide Choi,
and Castle Beauty's Exec Ops on board,
we'll make it happen.
I want to question every attendant,
Royal Guard, and official
in the vicinity of the Council Hall
at the time of the incident.
Uh, that would fall
under the Inner Court's jurisdiction.
I'll ask for cooperation
from the Queen Mother's Quarters.
No need.
I'll just ask her myself.
Is I-AN all right?
I wanted to visit him
at Anhwadang Hall, but…
Worried that he might actually…
pull through?
It happened as he was
about to accept the abdication.
And Your Majesty was the only one
who was against it.
Grand Princess, I…
If you don't want to be a suspect,
grant me unfettered access
to the palace attendants' shift records.
His Royal Highness will pull through.
That's the only way…
you make it out of this unscathed.
Oh…
I'm afraid I don't accept drinks
so freely anymore.
And the investigation?
When will it begin?
The Royal Protection Branch
will start it first,
and the police will join later.
It will not be public.
Why not public?
It came from the prime minister.
With the poisoning case still open,
he wanted to keep things from escalating.
He should be at Anhwadang Hall now.
Who?
- Prime Minister Min?
- Yes.
Did you run over here?
He should've been awake by now,
but I hadn't heard anything yet.
Right.
The royal physician said he's
in a near-comatose state due to stress.
It's a sign his body is recovering,
so he should be waking up soon.
When is "soon"?
Well, that is…
Apparently, there's no way of knowing.
Let's give it some time.
You didn't need to see me out.
Sorry.
Maybe it's everything
that's been going on.
I'm a little on edge.
By the way, don't you go
to the cathedral anymore?
What?
You're not wearing your rosary.
It gets in the way when I work.
Right.
Get back safely.
Thanks.
What's wrong?
Huiju hasn't texted back yet?
No.
Let's eat.
What should we get?
This place is known for…
- At the palace?
- Yeah.
Someone definitely died there.
Why else would they refuse
to make an official statement?
No way.
I did hear the explosion was really loud.
I read this rumor post…
It said Grand Prince I-AN…
is dead.
Oh, this…
- Babe, you need to call Huiju now.
- Okay.
Would it kill her to pick up
on the first try?
- She's not picking up? Let me try.
- Okay.
INCOMING CALL
GREMLIN
Sir.
I'm a little tired today.
Can we save it for tomorrow?
The Royal Secretariat wants
to release a statement.
The reason being?
There's a rumor circulating
that the Grand Prince has passed away.
The string of canceled public appearances
has also raised concerns.
There's even talk
the Grand Princess is in a critical state.
That should be
more than enough.
What on earth are you talking about?
What do you mean, regency?
Public concern is growing
over the welfare of the Crown.
However, His Majesty is unable
to carry out state affairs.
Since the Grand Prince
remains unconscious,
it would only be fitting
for Your Majesty to step forward.
The Grand Prince will wake up soon.
- The Grand Princess said...
- That is why
I have come here in such a hurry.
Ending the Grand Prince's regency
was no simple matter.
Likewise, once Your Majesty
takes up the regency,
it will not be easily undone.
Even if the Grand Prince wakes up.
That would be a rash decision.
- There is still time...
- Your Majesty.
If the notion bothers you so…
"Fulfill your duties to the Crown
as a representative of the people."
I can make it an official order.
So what will it be?
Your Majesty.
Grand Prince I-AN has arrived.
I-AN…
Please forgive me
for causing you concern, Your Majesty.
Did I…
cause you much distress?
SAJEONGJEON HALL WEST ENTRANCE
ACCESS LOG
I expected there would be a lot,
but this is unreal.
Even if it's extensive,
attendants follow a strict routine,
so any irregularities will stand out.
Plus, only a few
have access to the Council Hall.
Right.
Your Royal Highness!
The Grand Prince is awake!
You shouldn't have been there.
If something happened to you…
How could I possibly stay out…
…when I knew you were in there?
I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
When did you wake up?
Just now.
Have you seen the royal physician?
It was just a long nap.
He says I'm fine.
I'll resume my public duties at once.
Don't worry.
First, we should let you fully recover.
Prime Minister Min.
I hear rumors of my passing
are spreading outside these walls.
Now is the perfect time
to turn public opinion.
Since the Grand Prince
has regained consciousness,
it's time we tied up some loose ends.
LORD INPYEONG
Are you sure you're okay now?
I told you I'm fine.
Shall I call for
the royal physician again?
So…
why did you go see the Queen Mother
as soon as you woke up?
To see Prime Minister Min.
Jeongwoo?
With my waking being uncertain,
he would have to find someone
to take my place.
"Take your place"?
Are you saying he asked
the Queen Mother to act as regent?
So did you go there
to show them you're alive and well?
Yeah.
Listen.
How much
do you trust Jeongwoo?
That's random.
I mean, you two are friends,
but it's so impersonal
between you two sometimes.
Like that time with the contract.
There are times I want to punch him.
- What?
- But…
I've always trusted him.
Why?
Because I know
just as I'm bound by the Crown,
he's bound by the Cabinet.
Why do you ask?
Weren't you the one who said it was
only common sense to trust him?
Come here.
There he is!
The arsonist responsible
for the fire at Gyeongbokgung Palace
turned himself in last night.
During questioning, the suspect, Shin,
was identified as a member
of the Royal Guard.
An assassination suspect emerging
from the very force sworn
to protect the Crown
is sending shock waves nationwide.
Remove him!
He was also confirmed
to have protested
for the Grand Prince to step down.
How amusing.
It's as if they timed it to my waking.
Your Majesty,
Grand Prince I-AN has arrived.
Show him in.
Uncle!
Your Majesty.
Are you well?
Yes, that is why I am here.
The fire at the Council Hall…
I thought you would end up like Father…
Do not think such thoughts.
I will
always be by Your Majesty's side.
I heard the Grand Prince and Princess
are to resume their public duties.
This is their chance.
They will not let it go to waste.
Compassion and pity are but fleeting.
You must stop them from resuming
until that fleeting moment passes.
What makes you think
they will listen to me?
Your Majesty!
The Grand Prince nearly lost
his life in a gas explosion.
Use his welfare as grounds
to keep them from resuming their duties.
Father.
How did you know the fire was caused
by a gas explosion?
What exactly are you getting at?
That fact was withheld from the public.
So how do you know about that?
Your Majesty.
What is the matter?
Your Majesty, you must steady yourself.
It appears I will not
be able to protect you.
Your Majesty…
However, I shall see to it…
that your family is kept safe.
Your grace is boundless, Your Majesty.
Seriously?
How could one measly royal guard
blow up the Council Hall by himself?
My thoughts exactly.
The Royal Protection Branch is looking
for accomplices and co-conspirators...
- I need to leave the palace.
- Leave the palace?
Your Royal Highness,
the Queen Mother has arrived.
Show her in.
You may leave.
What brings you here?
Your Majesty.
Please stand up.
I have come…
to report a grave offense.
My father…
is trying to kill you.
This is the evidence
from the incident on your wedding day.
PERSONAL DETAILS: LEE AREUM
I also have the girl who used to work
at your private residence.
She has sworn to testify.
What is your intent in reporting this?
The recent fire…
It was likely my father's doing.
So?
Are you here to beg
for his forgiveness?
I am asking you to exact punishment.
Punish me…
and my father.
Did you believe me incapable of it?
And should I choose to do so…
are you sure you can handle it?
I shall try.
It's almost hunting season.
Right, since harvest season is
just around the corner.
Tell them I will be declaring
hunting season this year.
And not the royal family?
The Grand Prince needs time to recover,
and the Queen Mother
does not appreciate hunting.
Then I'll do it.
I guess I can do it.
Is it because I am accepting
the royal edict?
Why?
Why do you fear me now?
It is not that I fear you.
I have…
a duty to protect the Crown.
Thus, I am protecting you.
I am ensuring that neither my father
nor my own greed
ever harm you or the Crown again.
So please…
Just spare…
His Majesty.
As great as the honor once was…
so too shall your disgrace be.
In both the royal family and history,
you will forever remain a sinner.
If that is the price to spare His Majesty…
would you accept?
It is more than enough.
But…
"hunting season" in the 21st century?
What about animal rights?
Think of it as a necessary evil.
When harmful entities multiply…
we can't protect what matters.
And who determines that?
The Crown?
The nation.
I see.
So, you decide.
I saw you caught the guy.
Was he a harmful entity too?
Hey. I'm on my way back.
You're where?
He's a little drunk.
He's drunk?
Gosh. He can't even hold his liquor…
Boy, I'm tired. Who wants coffee?
Me.
Your Royal Highness.
My dear wife.
This is great.
I was feeling cooped up anyway.
You were?
Yeah.
The palace is so much bigger,
but far more stifling.
Agreed.
The Queen Mother came to see me earlier.
She told me Lord INPYEONG…
was behind the wedding incident.
Seeing her beg so desperately
to spare His Majesty…
I no longer know what I am to do.
You have such a gentle heart.
It breaks my heart.
THE THIRTY-THIRD KING
It will reach him this time, won't it?
I believe so.
I shall entrust it to you.
Rest assured, Your Majesty.
I heard you asked for me.
I wanted to commend you
for your swift arrest
of the arsonist.
The police deserve the credit.
I am well aware that nothing in this realm
is beyond your reach.
However,
are you still far from concluding
the poisoning case?
It won't be long now.
Lord INPYEONG of the Yun Family.
He is the culprit.
In terms of punishment,
I'm still deliberating.
About Prime Minister Min…
Be wary of him.
What does that mean?
He was the first
to discover my father's crimes.
- That is not possible.
- He knew everything,
but chose to keep it from you.
He would have no reason to do that.
Do you truly believe that?
How much
do you trust Jeongwoo?
Those driven by desperate desire…
often resort to unseemly choices.
What is there to consider?
As someone who is concerned
for the Crown's welfare,
I have much to consider.
He tried to kill me.
He's also the Queen Mother's father.
- Prime Minister Min.
- And His Majesty's grandfather.
- Min Jeongwoo.
- Please!
Stop acting like a child.
Lord INPYEONG will…
…never set foot in this realm again.
He will…
carry out his sentence in this realm.
Do you wish to see the Crown crumble?
Is there any reason why it should not?
The Crown…
cannot last forever.
Once I ascend the throne,
I will abolish the monarchy.
You've attained
everything you ever wanted.
And now you seek freedom as well?
This freedom…
won't be mine alone.
Are you okay?
Lord INPYEONG will be arrested soon.
Did Jeongwoo
agree to it?
No.
But he'll have no other choice.
I told him I knew…
and that I would not forgive him.
And what you wanted to confirm?
Did you?
No.
The first-ever compulsory investigation
into a royal relative has been conducted.
The Royal Protection Branch and police
announced they have obtained evidence
that proves Lord INPYEONG's involvement
in Grand Princess Seong's poisoning.
Authorities raided his home
and a research facility affiliated
with the Royal Seoul Hospital.
ROYAL PROTECTION BRANCH
- Look!
- There she is!
The joint investigation task
force stated shipment records of a drug
containing the same substance
administered to the Grand Prince,
as well as a testimony from a staff member
at his private residence, proved decisive.
With a royal relative suspected
in an attempted murder of a royal,
the fallout is expected to be significant.
Your Majesty.
His Majesty has arrived.
Mother.
Your Majesty.
Yes?
You must remain strong.
If you ever feel scared,
you should go to your uncle.
Do you understand?
Yes, Mother.
Your Royal Highness.
This is a misunderstanding.
Why would I ever…
Shut…
that mouth of yours.
History will remember you as a criminal,
and the Crown
will forget you ever existed.
I am His Majesty's grandfather
and the Queen Mother's father.
You cannot treat me like...
Did I not ask you…
to shut that mouth of yours?
The Queen Mother was the one
who told me about your crimes.
Thus…
you should mind your conduct.
The Queen Mother's welfare…
will depend on how deeply…
you repent.
You did well, Your Royal Highness.
The abdication has been announced.
Public sentiment is strong,
and the foreign media is all over it,
calling it long overdue.
- Let's go to the palace.
- Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Abolition?
How dare anyone suggest
to abolish the monarchy?
Why do we spend all that tax money
preserving the Crown?
Because the investment generates
enough added value to justify the cost.
If the economic and diplomatic benefits
of the Crown vanish,
who exactly will be held accountable?
The people will be up in arms about it.
I'm sure such news will have them
demanding a new king immediately.
That is exactly why…
…we must make him listen.
You must be busy with the coronation.
The Grand Prince told me.
That you had been aware
of what Lord INPYEONG did.
Then what about you?
Did you know?
That he's looking to abolish the monarchy.
A king
doesn't get to do whatever he wants.
My job is to make sure he doesn't.
What if it is a necessary evil?
What?
What if, in the 21st century,
our Crown itself turns out to be
the harmful entity?
What then?
I already told you.
That is for the nation to decide.
It appears…
we may end up as enemies.
Announcing His Majesty!
PERFECT CROWN
All rise
for His Majesty the King!
Your Majesty.
Abolition of the monarchy?
Is it true there are talks
of abolishing the monarchy?
You're saying the Cabinet
and Royal Relatives
will oppose it, no question?
Most of the establishment
is connected to the Crown.
Voice your objection there.
Simply hint that…
…is His Majesty's own pursuit.
What summons?
It's a slush fund probe.
And the Cabinet implored me
to fulfill my duties as the King.
We were simply speaking
on behalf of the public.
Go and protect His Majesty.
It's your fault.
Translated by Justin S. Kim.
PERFECT CROWN